# **Ibrahim Ahmed Amin AlRayyan**

**Frontend Engineer** 

# **Objectives**

Intensive Frontend Engineer with +3 years expertise in UI, JavaScript/ES6/ES12, React area with a strong understanding of React ecosystem and have a good experience in mobile cross-platform using React Native with a good knowledge of Node JS backend development. Besides that, I have strong fundamentals of Typescript and I have used it in a large-scale project.

#### Contacts

Mobile: (+20) 1007839923



• **Email:** Ibrahim.alrayany@gmail.com

• LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/RayyanX95

# Work Experience

# **VOIS** Nov 2022 – Present

I am working as a frontend engineer specialized using React.

Develop new features, fix bugs. Create and merge PRs. Deploy PRs using Jenkins.

# DXPR Apr 2022 – Present

I am working as a frontend engineer specialized.

I am fixing UI issues, adding new feature to the <u>dxpr\_builder</u> product. Also, I am transforming existing jQuery codes to be in Vanilla JavaScript. Sometimes acts as scrum master

# Terkwaz Dec 2019 – March 2022

I am working as a frontend engineer specialized in React. I create reusable components to be used cross the project and writes clean code that is readable and maintainable. I have been using a ton of UI libraries such as <u>Vuexy</u>, <u>Feather Icons</u>, <u>Atlaskit</u>, <u>Formik</u> for forms and input validation, <u>Drapzoe</u> for file uploading. Also using <u>react-table-6</u> for applying a high-performance pagination principle.

# **Projects**

Makanat Sep 2021 – Present

Makanat is on a mission to bring people together to meet, create, and celebrate.

**Gokwaz** July 2021 – Sep 2021

Gokwaz is a Jordanian-based delivery company that helps online and offline merchants and sellers. I am working on its admin panel.

Blink Dec 2019 – Present

Working on <u>Blink</u> since Dec 2019, it is a USA-based loan system with a huge code base and a complicated business logic. I gained a lot of experience during working on it specially skills of working on multi-national environment as it is a USA-based product and skills of working on huge code base projects. I cannot share it because it is an internal system.

**Hemma** July 2020 – Dec 2020

<u>Hemma</u> is e-learning platform, I worked on its admin panel. I have been working enhancing the UI and creating reusable components.

### Education

- **B.S.** in Computer Science and Engineering, Faculty of Electronic Engineering, Menofia University.
- Graduated at: July 2019
   Average grade: very good

#### Skills

#### Front End & Mobile

- Solid understanding of React echo system and for both classbased and functional components.
- **Typescript** for static typing with React for +2 years.
- Unit Testing using Jest and Enzyme
- Basics of Angular and Vue
- Cross-platform mobile using React-Native.
- Redux, Redux-thunk, and Redux-Saga for state management.
- HTML5, CSS3, JSX, bootstrap and responsive design.
- JS Tasks Runners and Bundlers (Webpack, Gulp, Grunt, and Browserify)

Mar 2022

Oct 2018

Basics of SSR React framework Next.js.

#### **Back End and Databases**

- Good knowledge of Node JS and Express JS.
- Good knowledge of SQL, NoSQL and Firebase.

### **Software Apps**

- VS Code Advanced setup
- Management Apps: Atlassian and Notion
- Windows and Linux CLI
- Integrate **Docker** with **WSL**
- GitHub Actions

### **Software Development**

- Solid understands of JavaScript and TypeScript
- JavaScript Design Patterns
- Algorithms and Problems Solving.
- **Software Engineering:** Agile
- Control version: GitHub, Gitlab and BitBucket
- Good knowledge of linting using Eslint

# Personal Projects (click on App name for more details)

Click Counter (unit-testing)

Burger Builder

### Front End (React)

•	Infinity Scroll (Vanilla JS)	Mar 2022
•	Raw23 Algasa	Oct 2019
•	<u>Animov</u>	July 2019
•	<u>Converto</u>	May 2019
•	Background Video	Nov 2018

#### **Courses** (click on the course (hyperlink) for more details)

•	Algorithms in JS from Scratch	
•	CSS - The Complete Guide	June 2022
•	step-by-step guide to Git	Sep 2021
•	MERN Full-stack Guide	Sep 2021
•	Typescript: Complete Guide	July 2021

#### Mobile (React Native)

Animov Sep 2019Share Place Aug 2019

• **Favorite Contacts:** for saving contacts info (their numbers, Facebook, Instagram). (Release soon)

#### **MERN Full-Stack**

Share Places
 Aug 2021
 A MERN full-stack application to share places

**HTML Fundamentals** (Sololearn)

•	Bootstrap 4 From Scratch	Dec 2021
•	React Testing (Jest & Enzyme)	June 2021.
•	React - The Complete Guide	July 2019.
•	Web Development (IBM)	July 2019
•	How to Start in React (Udemy)	May 2019

Jan 2018

# **Extracurricular Activities**

• 4<sup>th</sup> place in IBM digital nation, for digital solution of environmental problems in Africa. Aug to Oct 2019

• **2**<sup>nd</sup> place **in Nokia Africathon**, for digital solution of Africa (education). Aug to Oct 2019

• 1st Place FEE Control Exhibition Competition – Faculty of Electronic Engineering Apr 2018

• 3<sup>rd</sup> Place "Fekretk" Competition –Toshiba Alraby Company

Dec 2017

# Languages

• Arabic: Native

• English: Professional